Inventory of the Joseph Earle Jacobs papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Joseph Earle Jacobs papers
1909-1971
69071
Hoover Institution Archives
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Writings, correspondence, reports, and printed matter relating to various aspects of American diplomacy, especially reconstruction in Korea, mutual security programs in Europe after World War II, the Italian communist movement, the Philippine independence movement, and the Shanghai riot of May 30, 1925.
Jacobs, Joseph E., 1893-1971
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1969.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1893 October 31 Born, Johnston, South Carolina
1913 A.B., College of Charleston
1915 November 5 Student interpreter in China and detailed to Peking
1917-1918 Vice Consul, Foochow
1918 Vice Consul and interpreter, Shanghai
1918-1925 American Assessor, International Mixed Court, Shanghai
1919-1920 Judge, Consular Court, District of Shanghai
1921 Appointed Consul
1924 Reclassified as foreign service officer
1925 May-December Administrative Consul, Shanghai
1926 Technical Adviser to American Commissioner on Extraterritorial Jurisdiction in China
1926-1928 Consul, Yumanfu, China
1928-1930 Consul, Shanghai
1929 December-1930 February Representative of American Minister to China in negotiations with regard to the Provisional Court, Shanghai
1930 August 23 Married Elizabeth McNutt
1930-1934 Duty, Far Eastern Division, Department of State
1935-1936 Foreign Service Inspector
1936-1940 Chief, Office of Philippine Affairs, Department of State
1937 Member, Joint Committee of Experts on Philippine Affairs
1940-1945 Counselor of Legation, Cairo, Egypt
1945 January Attached to Political Adviser, Allied Headquarters, Mediterranean Command, Caserta, Italy
1945 May-1946 November American Representative to Albania
1947-1948 Political Adviser to the Commanding General in Korea
1947 November Career Minister, U.S. Foreign Service
1948 Adviser, Far Eastern Affairs, 3rd session of the General Assembly of the United Nations, Paris
1948-1949 U.S. Ambassador to Czechoslovakia
1949 Awarded Patriotic Civilian Service Medal by Department of the Army
1949-1955 Minister to American Embassy, Rome - special assistant for Mutual Defense Assistant Program
1953 LL.D., College of Charleston
1955-1957 U.S. Ambassador to Poland
1971 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings, correspondence, reports, and printed matter relating to various aspects of American diplomacy, especially reconstruction in Korea, mutual security programs in Europe after World War II, the Italian communist movement, the Philippine independence movement, and the Shanghai riot of May 30, 1925.
United States. Department of State.; Communism--Italy.; Diplomats--United States.; Nationalism--Philippines.; Reconstruction (1939-1951)--Korea (South); Textile Workers' Strike, Shanghai, China, 1925.; United States--Foreign relations.
- Political Adviser to the Commanding General in Korea file
  - Press release on Korea and the Soviet Union, 1948 April 9 (Box-folder 1: 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes two newspaper clippings, one in Korean.
  - U.S. Foreign Service reports on Syngman Rhee, the establishment of the Korean government, etc. (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - "Intimate Report on Syngman Rhee" (8 pp.), 1948 February 9
    - Syngman Rhee to John R. Hodge (3 pp.), 1948 August 6
    - Memorandum (2 pp.), 1948 August 12
    - Memorandum, re arrival of Douglas MacArthur (3 pp.), 1948 August
    - Press release, Rhee address (4 pp.), 1948 August 15
    - Press release, MacArthur address (2 pp.), 1948 August 15
    - Press release, Gen. John Hodge's remarks (3 pp.), 1948 August 15
    - Speech of H.E. Ambassador Liu Yu-wan (1 p.), 1948 August 15
    - Address of Rev. P. J. Byrne (2 pp.), 1948 August 15
    - Enclosure #2 to despatch No. 270, "List of Officials of Government of Republic of Korea,", 1948 August 21
    - Press release re Jacobs' return to Washington, 1948 August 25
    - Memorandum for Jacobs, re establishment of government of South Korea, 1948 November 3
    - Booklet, "Korea Reborn"
  - South Korean political matters, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - Material re visit of Lt. General A. C. Wedemeyer, etc. to Korea (30 pp.), 1947 August 26-September 3
    - Liaison and Consular Officials attached to the U.S. Army Forces in Korea (2 pp.), 1948 August 1
    - American Delegation, U.S.-U.S.S.R. Joint Commission, Political Advisory Group (7 pp.), 1947 August 2
    - Official letter of by Jacobs to Secretary of State, regarding Pyongyang Conference (4 pp.), 1948 May 3
    - Airgram, Jacobs to Department of State, re disorder on Cheju Island (3 pp.), 1948 May 4
    - Memorandum, regarding threats to representative of Korea from North Korean radio broadcasts (17 pp.), 1948 December 1
    - "What Is a Korean National Youth?" (5 pp.), 1947 January 28
    - "The Spirit of Korean Chivalry,", 1947 January 29
    - Despatch enclosure regarding the South Korea Labor Party (6 pp.), 1948 March 28
    - Letter, Jacobs to Secretary of State, regarding Kimm Kivsic - Kim Koo Unification Movement (2 pp.), 1948 August 4
  - Despatches, memoranda, and printed matter, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - Memorandum for General Wedemeyer, subject: "Comments on Memorandum dated July 15, 1947,", 1947 August 22
    - Memorandum for General Wedemeyer, subject: "Political Observations on Korea,", 1947 August 23
    - Memorandum for General Wedemeyer, subject: "Recommendations With Regard to Korea,", 1947 August 29
    - Memorandum for General Wedemeyer, subject: "Some Highlights of United States Policy Toward Korea,", 1947 September 2
    - Memorandum, South Korean Interim Government, subject: "Cost of Occupation - Military government" (4 pp.), 1948 April 29
    - Memorandum, subject: "Concert for the American Delegation,", 1947 July 2
    - Memorandum, "People killed in South Korea from 01 January 1948 to 26 April 1948" (1 p.)
    - Despatches No. 1028, 1029, to the State Department, (4 pp. each), 1948 July 8
    - Despatches No. 961, 962, to the State Department (9 pp., 8 pp.), 1948 June 26
    - Despatches No. 923, No. 924, to the State Department (4 pp. each), 1948 June 21
    - Despatches No. 917, 918, to the State Department (8 pp., 4 pp.), 1948 June 19
    - Despatch No. 829 (1 p.), 1948 June 8
    - Despatch No. 736 (7 pp.), 1948 May 26
    - Despatch (carbon), to State Department (8 pp.), 1948 February 12
    - Note on American expenditures (1 p.)
    - Copy of State Department telegram (No. 142) (3 pp.), 1947 July 14
    - Press conference of General Hodge (off the record), 1948 May 7
    - TiP (Troop information Program) newsletter, "The Progress and Problems of the Joint Commission,", 1947 August 15
    - "The Occupation of Korea," Foreign Policy Reports, by George M. McCune, 1947 October 15
  - Printed material on Korea, booklets, newspapers, periodical clippings (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - U.N. Temporary Commission on Korea, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - Telegram #361 to Dept., 1947 September 19
    - Letter to Lt. Gen. John Hodge from Maj. Gen. C. A. Willoughby (3 pp.), 1948 July 15
    - Memorandum, State Department Office of Intelligence Research, "Moscow Radio Criticism of the United Nations and the United Nations Temporary Commission on Korea" (23 pp.), 1948 November 1
    - Memorandum, "Description of the Interim Committee Proceedings on Korea, Feb. 19-26, 1948" (19 pp.), 1948 April 14
    - Despatch No. 184, to Secretary of State regarding "Draft documents... (of) Australian delegate...at 65th and 66th Plenary Sessions of the U.N. Commission on Korea," plus enclosures (6 pp.), 1948 June 24
    - U.S. Mission to the United Nations, Soviet statements in Comm. I, General Assembly, 2nd Session V, "The Problem of the Independence of Korea" (38 pp.), 1948 August 31
  - Joint U.S.-U.S.S.R. Commission on Korea, reports and positions, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the U.S.S.R., "The Soviet Union and the Korean Question - Documents," Moscow, 1948
    - Joint communiqué (12 pp.), 1947 June 12-11
    - U.S. Foreign Service, No. 24, subject: "Methods of Dealing with Soviet Officials" (6 pp.), 1948 February 6
    - U.S. Foreign Service, No. 97, subject: "Visit to Seoul of Underseer of Army, Wm. H. Draper," plus attachment (7 pp.), 1947 September 26
    - U.S. Foreign Service, No. 102, subject: "Visit to Seoul of Underseer of Army, Wm. H. Draper,", 1947 September 30
    - U.S. Foreign Service, No. 126, subject: "Visit to Seoul of members of intrastate and foreign commerce congressional committee" (2 lv.), 1947 October 21
    - Drafts on thoughts re Korea, in letter form to Hugh Borton, State Department (12 pp.), 1947 July 25
    - List of dates of Joint Commission meetings - meetings 38-62 (1 leaf), 1947
    - Soviet proposal re plan of work in Pyongyang during 30 June - 3 July 1947 (2 lv.), 1947 July 23
    - "Position of the Soviet Delegation," 48th meeting (5 lv.), 1947 July 29
    - "Position of the Soviet Delegation," 49th meeting (3 lv.), 1947 July 31
    - "Position of the Soviet Delegation," 50th meeting (3 lv.), 1947 August 1
    - "Position of the Soviet Delegation," 51st meeting (3 lv.), 1947 August 5
    - "Position of the Soviet Delegation," 52nd meeting (4 lv.), 1947 August 7
    - "Position of the Soviet Delegation," 53rd meeting (carbons, 6 pp.), 1947 August 12
    - "Position of the Soviet Delegation," 54th meeting, 1947 August 20
    - "Position of the Soviet Delegation," 55th meeting, 1947 August 20
    - "Position of the Soviet Delegation," 56th meeting (7 lv.), 1947 August 26
    - "Position of the Soviet Delegation," 57th meeting (8 lv.), 1947 September 3
    - Draft, U.S. position on freedom of expression and eligibility for consultation (re Korean government statements) (4 lv.), 1947 June 28
    - List of Soviet objections to parties and Social organizations (1 leaf), 1947 July
    - Observations of Interpreter of Joint Commission trip to Pyongyang (10 pp.), 1947 June 29-July 3
    - Korean organizations in the U.S., as of 16 October 1947 (3 lv.)
    - Notes on Korean politics compiled by the Political Advisory Group, American delegation, U.S.-U.S.S.R. Joint Committee in cooperation of G-2, Hg. XXIV Corps, 1947 September 1
  - "Notes on Korean Politics,", 1947 (Box-folder 1: 8-9)
  - Joint U.S.-U.S.S.R. Commission on Korea, invitations and programs, 1947 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Telephone directory, Greater Seoul Area, 1948 March 1 (Box-folder 1: 11)
- Communism in Italy, embassy reports and printed matter, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  Includes a preliminary report on the VII Congress of the Italian Communist Party and a map of Italy showing communist areas.
- Joint Committee in the Philippines, report and press release (5 pp.), 1937-1939 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  Includes a press release of 1939 August 7 regarding the bill to amend the Philippine Independence Act.
- Netherland India
  - Tourist booklets and guides, circa 1935 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    Titles include "A Short Guide to the Boro-Budur," "Dutch East Indies, Indo-China, Malaya, Siam," "Tourist Map: Bali and the Idjen-Highland," "The Best of Java," "Sumatra," "Bali," and "Handbook of Information and Intended Time Table: K.P.M. Line."
  - Tourist booklets and guides, circa 1935 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- International Mixed Court, Shanghai, trial, 1925 (Box-folder 2: 2-5)
- Correspondence
  Mainly personal correspondence documenting Jacobs' various appointments with in the Department of State. Includes a series of letters relating to his forced resignation as Ambassador to Czechoslovakia by President Truman and correspondence with friend Alger Hiss.
  - 1922-1924 (Box-folder 3: 1)
    Includes one photograph, undated.
  - 1925-1927 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - 1928-1930 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - 1933-1936 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - 1937-1939 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - 1940-1942 (Box-folder 3: 6)
    Includes newspaper clipping from the Manila Daily Bulletin, 1940 September 10.
  - 1945-1946 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - 1947-1948 (Box-folder 3: 8)
    Includes newspaper clipping in Czech, 1948 December 19.
  - 1949 (Box-folder 3: 9)
    Includes newspaper clipping from the New York Times, 1949 June 16.
  - 1950-1954 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - 1955-1956 (Box-folder 3: 11)
    Includes two photographs, 1955.
  - 1957 (Box-folder 3: 12)
- Official orders, 1946-1955 (Box-folder 3: 13)
- Material related to U.S. involvement in China, 1915-1926 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  Includes correspondence, memoranda on judicial procedure, 1922 congressional resolution and presidential proclamation, 1921 executive order, 1915 booklet titled "Outlines of the System of Civil Government in China," and newspaper clippings.
- Congressional report and act, 1909, 1922 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  Report of the Sixtieth Congress, Session II, and "An Act Relative to the Naturalization and Citizenship of Married Women."
- "Reports on the Peculiarities of Consular Service Work in China Under Extraterritoriality," report and correspondence, 1920 (Box-folder 3: 16)
- Obituaries, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 3: 17)